Recreational Services and Athletics fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Sports Information Office files, 1965 - 1994; F-80-10; 96 cm of textual records; Physical description: 81 photographs located in F-80-10-4-1 Physical description: 57 photographs located in F-80-10-4-2 Physical description: 36 photographs located in F-80-10-4-3 Physical description: 57 photographs 
  - Sports Information Office files - photographs, 1971 - 1993; F-80-10-4; 36 cm of textual records 29.5 cm of photographic material
    - Men's basketball, 1989 - 1990; F-80-10-4-0-5 (Archival box - standard 80-26)
    - Women's basketball, 1989 - 1990; F-80-10-4-0-6 (Archival box - standard 80-26)
    - Men's golf, 1987 - 1989; F-80-10-4-0-7 (Archival box - standard 80-26)
    - Golf, 1990; F-80-10-4-0-8 (Archival box - standard 80-26)
    - Skiing, 1983 - 1989; F-80-10-4-0-9 (Archival box - standard 80-26)
    - Skiing, 1986 - 1989; F-80-10-4-0-10 (Archival box - standard 80-26)
    - Skiing, 1990 - 1991; F-80-10-4-0-11 (Archival box - standard 80-26)
    - Daryl Larson [soccer photographs and press clippings], 1971 - 1989; F-80-10-4-0-12 (Archival box - standard 80-27)
    - Men's soccer, 1987; F-80-10-4-0-13 (Archival box - standard 80-27)
    - Men's soccer, 1988; F-80-10-4-0-14 (Archival box - standard 80-27)
    - Women's soccer, 1988 - 1989; F-80-10-4-0-15 (Archival box - standard 80-27)
    - Women's soccer, 1989; F-80-10-4-0-16 (Archival box - standard 80-27)
    - Men's soccer, 1989 - 1990; F-80-10-4-0-17 (Archival box - standard 80-27)
    - Swimming, 1985 - 1986; F-80-10-4-0-18 (Archival box - standard 80-27)
    - Track and field, 1986 - 1993; F-80-10-4-0-19 (Archival box - standard 80-27)
    - Track and field - unfiled photographs, 1986 - 1993; F-80-10-4-0-20 (Archival box - standard 80-27)
    - Cross country, 1988; F-80-10-4-0-21 (Archival box - standard 80-28)
    - Staff photographs, [ca 1990]; F-80-10-4-0-22 (Archival box - standard 80-28)
- Audio visual records, [ca 1967] - [1976?]; F-80-11; 62 moving images; Physical description: 62 moving images on 34 film reels, 39 videocassettes, 2 optical discs; some productions include multiple reels or copies.
  Series consists of audio visual materials made or received by SFU Recreational Services and Athletics in the course of its activities and programs. The majority of the items relate to the games and practices of the SFU football, with some additional material relating to the SFU basketball team.
  The series was arranged by the archivist into two sub-series based on content. Within sub-series, items are arranged chronologically.
  The physical condition of many of the films is poor; playing them on a sprocket driven machine would cause further damage. As of September 2012 digital access copies have been made for only two items (F-11-2-0-0-3 and F-11-2-0-0-4). Access to originals films is restricted. Please consult the archivist for more information regarding accessing these records.
  - Basketball films, [197-?] - [1976?]; F-80-11-1; 3 moving images; Physical description: 3 moving image productions on 8 film reels.
    Sub-series consists of films relating to the SFU basketball program.
    Items are arranged chronologically.
    Access to the original films is restricted due to the fragility of the medium. Please consult the archivist for more information regarding access to these records.
    - Free Flow, [197-?]; F-80-11-1-0-0-1 (Film reel OBJ-2123)
      Hildred, Chris; Dunn, John; Gyseman, Doug; Kootnekoff, John; Moving images
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item27.
    - SFU Basketball Techniques, 1972; F-80-11-1-0-0-2 (Film reel OBJ-2124, Film reel OBJ-2125, Film reel OBJ-2126, Film reel OBJ-2127)
      Rizak, Gene; Poole, Greg; Hancheboff, Harold; Bifano, Vic "Umberto"; Moving images
    - SFU Basketball AVC, 1972; F-80-11-1-0-0-3 (Film reel OBJ-2128, Film reel OBJ-2129, Film reel OBJ-2130)
      Moving images
  - Football films, [ca 1967] - 1973; F-80-11-2; 20 moving images; Physical description: 20 moving images on 26 film reels and 2 optical discs. All films are 16mm gauge. With one exception, all are on acetate base film; the exception is one of the reels for item 6, which has a polyester base.
    Series consists of films relating to the SFU men's football program. The majority of the items are silent amateur recordings of team games. Items 2 and 3, however, are kinescope film recordings of CBC productions relating to the first and second Shrum Bowl, the annual football game between SFU and UBC.
    Access to the original film reels is restricted due to the fragility of the medium. Digital access copies are available for two items (items 3 and 4). Consult the reference archivist for more information on accessing the other films.
    - SFU-UBC Crowds, Football, V.P.D., [ca 1967]; F-80-11-2-0-0-1 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2131)
      University of British Columbia (UBC); Moving images
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item1.
    - SFU vs UBC '67, TV highlights: SFU 32 - UBC 13, 1967; F-80-11-2-0-0-2 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2132)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item2.
    - Time Out For Football, November 9, 1967; F-80-11-2-0-0-3 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2133, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3270, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-4099)
      Episdoe of the CBC program Time Out for Football, a show that featured professional football with an emphasis on the BC Lions of the Canadian Football League. The episode of October 17, 1967 included a film feature that covered the first annual Shrum Bowl, a meeting between the football teams of SFU and UBC. The game took place on October 16, 1967 with SFU winning 32-13.
      The film includes the following shots (descriptions taken from the CBC catalogue entry): UBC campus B-Roll shots; interview with Gordon Shrum; shots in UBC Thunderbird locker room, players suiting up and voiceover comments from players about SFU; UBC players at practice with assistant coach voiceover comments and head coach Frank Gnup shots and voiceover comments; SFU players suiting up in their locker room and with player voiceover comments on UBC and the game; SFU team practice at Burnaby campus with voiceover comment from coaches, including head coach Lorne Davies. The game highlight package includes the opening kickoff by SFU player Dave Cutler; UBC opening drive; an SFU interception; UBC running gains and a second SFU interception; SFU quaterback Holmes scores a touchdown; UBC's Vic Iwata fumbles and SFU recovers; Iwata takes the opening kickoff of the second half; UBC's Bellamy runs back an interception; Hardy completes a UBC pass to Bellamy; SFU penalized for pass interference; UBC run for their first touchdown; Ron Ritchie makes a long punt return for a UBC touchdown. The game ends, Gordon Shrum presents the trophy to SFU. Ted Reynolds thanks cameramen Roy Luckow and Bob Reid as well as film editor Frank Irvine and Bob Smith ('Hot Air' host) script and narration. Reynolds responds to a viewer's question re: NFL vs. CFL football, and draws a name for a draw. The kinescope includes an animated Fred Asher "biography" of Stephen Leacock, and a public service announcement on allergies. Show concludes with Ted Reynolds on phone with BC Lions coach Jim Champion in Ottawa re: the injury situation with various Lions players and preps for the upcoming game against the Ottawa Rough Riders.
      Canadian Broadcasting Corporation; Reynolds, Ted; Champion, Jim; Roy Luckow; Reid, Bob; Frank Irvine; Smith, Bob (CBC); Fred Asher; Shrum, Gordon; Frank Gnup; Davies, Lorne W.; Cutler, Dave; Vic Iwata; Ron Ritchie; Stephen Leacock; University of British Columbia (UBC); Moving images
      Duration: 0
      Original was a kinescope made by CBC (a copy of a live television program made by filming the playback monitor). CBC subsequently gave a copy to SFU. Exact date of transfer to the SFU Archives not known. In May 2009, the SFU Archives sent its copy to CBC Archives for digitization. CBC returned the film to SFU Archives along with a digital copy and retained a digital copy for its own holdings.
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item3.
    - SFU-UBC Football, October 21, 1968; F-80-11-2-0-0-4 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2134, Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2135, Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2136, Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2137, Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2138, Optical discs OBJ-3271)
      The second annual Shrum Bowl football game between SFU and UBC, played in Vancouver's Empire Stadium on October 21, 1968. Item was originally created by CBC as a kinescope film recording of a live television program. The game announcers were Jim Cox and Bob Smith.
      Canadian Broadcasting Corporation; Cox, Jim; Smith, Bob (CBC); University of British Columbia (UBC); Moving images
      Duration: 2
      Original was a set of 5 kinescope films made by CBC (a copy of a live television program made by filming the playback monitor). CBC subsequently gave a copy to SFU. Exact date of transfer to the SFU Archives not known. In May 2009, the SFU Archives sent its copy to CBC Archives for digitization. CBC returned the film reels to SFU Archives along with a digital copy and retained a digital copy for its own holdings.
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item4, F-80-item5, F-80-item6, F-80-item7, F-80-item8.
    - Simon Fraser University Football Highlights 1970, F-80-11-2-0-0-5 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2139)
      Duration: 45
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item9.
    - SFU football highlights, 1971; F-80-11-2-0-0-6 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2140, Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2141, Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2142)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item10, F-80-item15, F-80-item16.
    - SFU-Riverside, September 26, 1971; F-80-11-2-0-0-7 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2143)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item11.
    - SFU vs. Puget Sound, November 6, 1971; F-80-11-2-0-0-8 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2144)
      University of Puget Sound; Moving images
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item14.
    - UBC vs SFU, November 13, 1971; F-80-11-2-0-0-9 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2145)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item12.
    - SFU vs Western Washington University, November 20, 1971; F-80-11-2-0-0-10 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2146)
      Western Washington University; Moving images
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item13.
    - SFU scrimmage, September 3, 1972; F-80-11-2-0-0-11 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2147)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item17.
    - SFU scrimmage, August 25, 1973; F-80-11-2-0-0-12 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2148)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item18.
    - SFU vs Pacific University, October 15, 1972; F-80-11-2-0-0-13 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2149)
      Pacific University; Moving images
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item19.
    - Montana at SFU, November 11, 1972; F-80-11-2-0-0-14 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2150)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item20.
    - Oregon College vs. SFU, November 25, 1972; F-80-11-2-0-0-15 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2151)
      Oregon College; Moving images
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item21.
    - SFU intersquad, September 1, 1973; F-80-11-2-0-0-16 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2152)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item23.
    - Portland State University vs SFU, September 15, 1973; F-80-11-2-0-0-17 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2153)
      Portland State University; Moving images
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item22.
    - Chico vs SFU, October 27, 1973; F-80-11-2-0-0-18 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2154)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item24.
    - UPS vs SFU, November 10, 1973; F-80-11-2-0-0-19 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2155)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item25.
    - CWSE vs SFU, November 17, 1973; F-80-11-2-0-0-20 (Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2156)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-80-item26.
  - Football videos, 1991 - 2001; F-80-11-4; 39 moving images
    Series consists of videos relating to the SFU men's football program. The majority of the videos are silent amateur recordings of team games.
    Moving images on 39 videocassettes.
    - Seattle University, January 26, 1991; F-80-11-4-0-0-1 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4987)
    - SFU vs Lewis & Clark, September 28, 1991; F-80-11-4-0-0-2 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4992)
    - SFU vs Whitworth, 41-30, October 17, 1992; F-80-11-4-0-0-3 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-5002)
    - SFU vs UBC Sept 12/93, 17-20, 1993; F-80-11-4-0-0-4; 1 videocassette 1 .mkv file (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4970)
      Moving images; Records in electronic form (digitized)
      OBJ-4970 also available in .mp4 format.
    - SFU vs WWU #1, 9-13, October 30, 1993; F-80-11-4-0-0-5; 1 videocassette 1 .mkv file (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4976)
      OBJ-4976 also available in .mp4 format
    - SFU vs Willamette, 15-42, September 17, 1994; F-80-11-4-0-0-6; 1 videocassette 1 .mov file (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4977)
      OBJ-4977 also available in .mp4 and .mkv formats.
    - SFU vs Linfield, 6-30, September 24, 1994; F-80-11-4-0-0-7; 1 videocassette 1 .mov file (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4982)
      Records in electronic form (digitized); Moving images
      .mov file also available in .mkv and .mp4 formats.
    - SFU vs University Puget Sound Oct 15/94, 1994; F-80-11-4-0-0-8; 1 videocassette 1 .mov file (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4971)
    - SFU vs Pacific Lutheran, 13-27, October 22, 1994; F-80-11-4-0-0-9; 1 videocassette 1 .mkv file (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4983)
      OBJ-4983 also available in .mp4 format.
    - SFU vs Central Washington, 0-57, November 5, 1994; F-80-11-4-0-0-10; 1 videocassette 1 .mkv file (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4973)
      OBJ-4973 also available in .mp4 format.
    - SFU vs Western Oregon, 7-27, 1995; F-80-11-4-0-0-11; 1 videocassette 1 mkv file (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4978)
    - SFU vs Southern Oregon State College, 16-15, 1995; F-80-11-4-0-0-12; 1 videocassette 1 .mkv file (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4974)
      OBJ-4974 also available in .mp4 format.
    - SFU vs Central Washington, 19-34, 1995; F-80-11-4-0-0-13 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4972)
    - SFU vs PLU 1st half, September 29, 1996; F-80-11-4-0-0-14 (Videocassette: edbeta OBJ-5007)
    - SFU vs WWU 98, 0-44, 1998; F-80-11-4-0-0-15 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4979)
    - UPS vs SFU, September 9, 1998; F-80-11-4-0-0-16 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4975)
    - SFU vs S. Oregon, October 3, 1998; F-80-11-4-0-0-17 (Videocassette: edbeta OBJ-5008)
    - Shrum Bowl, 1998; F-80-11-4-0-0-18 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4980)
    - SFU vs UPS, 1998; F-80-11-4-0-0-19 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4991)
    - SFU vs Pacific Lutheran, 20-27, [199?]; F-80-11-4-0-0-20 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4989)
    - Eastern vs SFU, 1st half endzone, [199?]; F-80-11-4-0-0-21 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4985)
    - SFU at Humboldt, January 28, 1999; F-80-11-4-0-0-22 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-5004)
    - SFU vs SOSC, 1999; F-80-11-4-0-0-23 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4988)
    - SFU vs Western Washington, January 20, 2000; F-80-11-4-0-0-24 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-5003)
    - Whitworth vs SFU, September 30, 2000; F-80-11-4-0-0-25 (Videocassette: edbeta OBJ-5009)
    - Western Oregon vs SFU, 2000; F-80-11-4-0-0-26 (Videocassette: edbeta OBJ-5006)
    - SFU vs Puget Sound, 24-20, September 9, 2000; F-80-11-4-0-0-27 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-5000)
    - SFU vs Pacific Lutheran, 28-42, September 16, 2000; F-80-11-4-0-0-28 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-5001)
    - SFU vs Eastern Oregon, 18-49, September 23, 2000; F-80-11-4-0-0-29 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4997)
    - SFU vs UBC, 28-41, October 6, 2000; F-80-11-4-0-0-30 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4995)
    - SFU vs Humboldt State, 21-31, October 14, 2000; F-80-11-4-0-0-31 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4998)
    - SFU vs Western Washington, 13-55, October 28, 2000; F-80-11-4-0-0-32 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4996)
    - SFU vs Western Oregon, 21-17, November 4, 2000; F-80-11-4-0-0-33 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4994)
    - SFU vs Central Washington, 24-38, November 11, 2000; F-80-11-4-0-0-34 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-5005)
    - SFU vs SOSC, 19-49, September 22, 2001; F-80-11-4-0-0-35 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4993)
    - SFU vs University of Puget Sound, 39-0, September 9, 2001; F-80-11-4-0-0-36 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4981)
    - SFU vs Whithworth, 20-23, September 29, 2001; F-80-11-4-0-0-37 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4990)
    - SFU vs Eastern Washington, 14-66, October 13, 2001; F-80-11-4-0-0-38 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4999)
    - E. Oregon vs SFU, October 20, 2001; F-80-11-4-0-0-39 (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4984)